Guide to the Harold Phelps Stokes Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Harold Phelps Stokes papers
1908-1969
MS 645
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
12.75
(24 boxes)
The papers consist of correspondence, diaries, memoranda, notes, writings, clippings, and subject files documenting the personal life and professional career of Harold Phelps Stokes. His interests in United States foreign policy and domestic politics, the Alger Hiss case, the Paris Peace Conference, New York City politics and government, prison reform, and journalism are documented. Stokes corresponded with many prominent American political and social figures.
Stokes, Harold Phelps, 1887-1970
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gifts from members of the family, 1969-1977.
Existence and Location of Copies
Newspaper clippings file is available on microfilm (7,040 frames on 7 reels, 35mm.) from Manuscripts and Archives, Yale University Library, at cost. Order no. HM108.
Biographical / Historical
Harold Phelps Stokes, the son of banker Anson Phelps Stokes and Helen Louisa (Phelps) Stokes, was born in New York City on January 10, 1887. He attended Groton and entered Yale University in 1905, where he studied Oriental history. Stokes graduated in 1909. He spent the following year travelling around the world with his classmate Allen Klots.
Returning to America in 1911, Stokes joined the staff of Oswald Garrison Villard's New York Evening Post. In 1913 he became the Post's Albany correspondent. He left this job in 1917 to serve with the 77th Division of the AEF. In 1919, Stokes rejoined the staff of the Post in Paris and reported the Peace Conference. Later that year, Stokes succeeded David Lawrence as head of the Post's Washington bureau. There he covered many important stories, including the debate on the Treaty of Versailles in the Senate and the conference for the limitation of armaments. In 1920, Stokes married Elizabeth Miner King, who was also a reporter.
After thirteen years with the New York Evening Post, Stokes resigned in 1923. For a while he wrote a syndicated column entitled "The A.B.C. of National Affairs." In 1924 he became secretary to Herbert Hoover, then Secretary of Commerce.
In 1926 Stokes joined the editorial staff of The New York Times. At the Times he specialized in writing about government in New York and about parole and prisons, traffic problems, and mass transit. He also was a frequent contributor to The New York Times Magazine. In 1937, ill health forced Stokes to resign from the Times. He lived in the West for a while before settling in Washington, D.C. He continued to do some free-lance writing and maintained an active interest in national and world affairs. He died in 1970 at the age of 83.
Scope and Contents
As a newspaperman, Stokes had a wide variety of interests. His papers span more than half a century and touch on many topics. One of Stokes' greatest concerns was the government of New York City and State. His work brought him into contact with political figures from throughout the state. As a reporter and editorial writer he was involved in many disputes on zoning, conservation, voter representation, patronage, and other political issues.
In addition to these topics, Stokes' correspondence and papers are concerned with subjects like foreign policy, parole and prison reform, public utilities, civil service reform, and the Alger Hiss case. The Stokes Papers also provide some insight into the policies and personalities behind the New York Evening Post. There is, however, very little material on Stokes' association with Herbert Hoover.
SERIES I. CORRESPONDENCE, contains letters from many prominent American politicians, newspapermen, and public servants. Among them are: Dean Gooderham Acheson (6 items), Norman H. Davis (7 items), John Huston Finley (5 items), John Palmer Gavit (14 items), Edwin F, Gay (12 items), Henry Hazlitt (5 items), Herbert Clark Hoover (13 items), Allen Trafford Klots (10 items), Arthur Krock (18 items), David Lawrence (5 items), George McAneny (16 items), Andrew William Mellon (2 items), Charles Merz (16 items), Robert Moses (67 items), Adolph S. Ochs (6 items), Frances Perkins (18 items), Alfred Emanuel Smith (12 items), Henry Lewis Stimson (12 items), Anson Phelps Stokes (1874-1958) (55 items), Simeon Strusky (37 items), Arthur Hays Sulzberger (36 items), Edward Livingstone Trudeau (15 items), Oswald Garrison Villard (18 items), and Robert Ferdinand Wagner (13 items).
SERIES II. DIARIES, MEMORANDA, NOTES AND WRITINGS contains manuscripts of material written by Stokes. This includes articles by Stokes, a diary of his trip around the world in 1910, and a diary of some events surrounding the conference for the limitation of armaments in 1921. Also in this series are numbers of memoranda and notes written by Stokes on various topics. The series includes a copy of Stokes'Dispatches 1919-1921 and a copy of his introductory essay for Simeon Strunsky's America. Letters to the editor, book reviews, and some newspaper-stories (clippings) are also filed in this section.
SERIES III. the NEWSPAPER FILE, consists of twenty-three bound volumes of newspaper clippings. The volumes cover December, 1913 to May, 1917; January, 1919 to March 1922; and January, 1923 to April, 1924. The two volumes for April to December, 1922 were not found with the collection and appear to be lost. The twenty-three volumes contain articles by Stokes and other newspapermen on domestic politics and foreign affairs. They are completely indexed on file cards. These volumes probably served Stokes as a reference and research tool in his work.
SERIES IV. the SUBJECT FILE, contains a variety of material on subjects of interest to Stokes. This material includes magazine articles, pamphlets, newspaper clippings, and other informational materials. Of particular interest is a large section of newspaper and magazine clippings on Alger Hiss. Also included is material used by Stokes in preparing his book Simeon Strunsky's America. A large amount of printed material on Robert Moses has been removed from this series and placed with the Robert Moses Papers, in Manuscripts and Archives, Sterling Memorial Library, Yale University.
Arrangement
Arranged in four series and additions: I. Correspondence. II. Diaries, Memoranda, Notes, and Writings. III. Newspaper File. IV. Subject File.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
New York post; New York times; Journalism; Newspapers; Prisons; Voyages around the world; World War, 1914-1918; Asia; Europe -- Description and travel; Germany; New York (N.Y.) -- Politics and government; New York (State) -- Politics and government; Soviet Union; United States -- Description and travel; United States -- Foreign relations; Diaries; Journalists; Acheson, Dean, 1893-1971; Andrews, Paul Shipman; Atkinson, Brooks, 1894-1984; Auchincloss, James Coats, 1885-; Bacon, Leonard, 1887-1954; Baker, Newton Diehl, 1871-1937; Baker, Ray Stannard, 1870-1946; Baker, Russell, 1925-; Barnes, William, 1866-1930; Bassett, Edward M. (Edward Murray), 1863-1948; Bates, Sanford, 1884-1972; Beaverbrook, Max Aitken, Baron, 1879-1964; Biddle, Francis, 1886-1968; Bundy, Harvey Hollister, 1888-1963; Bundy, McGeorge, 1919-1996; Butler, Nicholas Murray, 1862-1947; Capper, Arthur, 1865-1951; Carlisle, Floyd Leslie, 1881-; Catledge, Turner, 1901-1983; Cohen, Julius Henry, 1873-1950; Cross, Wilbur L. (Wilbur Lucius), 1862-1948; Danaher, John Anthony, 1899-; Darling, Jay N. (Jay Norwood), 1876-1962; Davis, Elmer Holmes, 1890-1958; Davis, John W. (John William), 1873-1955; Davis, Malcolm W. (Malcolm Waters), 1889-1970; Davis, Norman H. (Norman Hezekiah), 1878-1944; Dawes, Charles Gates, 1865-1951; Day, Clive, 1871-1951; Day, George Parmly, 1876-1959; Derounian, Steven B. (Steven Boghos), 1918-2007; Dirksen, Everett McKinley, 1896-1969; Dodd, Frank Courtenay, 1875-1968; Dodge, Cleveland E.; Douglas, Lewis W. (Lewis Williams), 1894-1974; Duffus, R. L. (Robert Luther), 1888-1972; Dun, Angus, bp., 1892-; Eisenhower, Dwight D. (Dwight David), 1890-1969; Finley, John H. (John Huston), 1863-1940; Franklin, Fabian, 1853-1939; Gault, Robert H. (Robert Harvey), 1874-1971; Gavit, John Palmer, 1868-1954; Gay, Edwin F. (Edwin Francis), 1867-1946; Gilbert, Seymour Parker, 1892-1938; Grenfell, Wilfred Thomason, Sir, 1865-1940; Gruening, Ernest, 1887-1974; Hadley, Arthur Twining, 1856-1930; Hard, William, 1878-1962; Hays, Will H. (Will Harrison), 1879-1954; Hayward, Walter Brownell, 1877-1957; Hazlitt, Henry, 1894-1993; Hester, Christian Archibald, 1895-1966; Hiss, Alger, 1904-1996; Hoover, Herbert, 1874-1964; Howells, John Mead, 1868-1959; Hughes, Charles Evans, 1862-1948; Hylan, John Francis, 1868-1936; James, Walter Belknap; Kaempffert, Waldemar, 1877-1956; Katzenbach, Nicholas deB. (Nicholas deBelleville), 1922-2012; Kelley, Nicholas, 1885-1965; Kennedy, John F. (John Fitzgerald), 1917-1963; Kent, Frank R. (Frank Richardson), 1877-1958; King, Henry Churchill, 1858-1934; Klots, Allen Trafford, 1889-1965; Krock, Arthur, 1886-1974; Lamont, Thomas W. (Thomas William), 1870-1948; Lansing, Robert, 1864-1928; Latourette, Kenneth Scott, 1884-1968; Laurence, William L., 1888-1977; Lawrence, David, 1888-1973; Leffingwell, R. C. (Russell Cornell), 1878-1960; Lehman, Herbert H. (Herbert Henry), 1878-1963; Lippmann, Walter, 1889-1974; Lohmann, Carl A. (Carl Albert), 1887-; Loomis, Alfred L. (Alfred Lee), 1887-1975; Lowry, Edward G. (Edward George), 1876-1943; MacAlarney, Robert Emmet, 1873-; MacVeagh, Lincoln, 1890-1972; Maltbie, Milo Roy, 1871-; Markel, Lester, 1894-; Mathews, William Rankin, 1893-; McAneny, George, 1869-1953; McClintock, Miller, 1894-1960; McFarland, J. Horace (John Horace), 1859-1948; McGoldrick, Joseph D. (Joseph Daniel), 1901-1978; McKee, Joseph V., -1956; McMahon, Brien, 1903-1952; Mellon, Andrew W. (Andrew William), 1855-1937; Merz, Charles, 1893-; Meyer, Eugene, 1875-1959; Mills, Ogden Livingston, 1884-1937; Moses, Robert, 1888-1981; Myers, Gustavus, 1872-1942; Nevins, Allan, 1890-1971; Nicholson, Seth B. (Seth Barnes), 1891-1963; Ochs, Adolph S. (Adolph Simon), 1858-1935; Ogden, Rollo, 1856-1937; Olmsted, Frederick Law, 1870-1957; Ordway, Samuel H., Jr., 1900-1971; Osborn, Henry Fairfield, 1857-1935; Osborn, Wm. Church (William Church), 1862-1951; Osborne, Lithgow, 1892-1980; Osborne, Thomas Mott, 1859-1926; Page, Arthur W. (Arthur Wilson), 1883-1960; Palmer, A. Mitchell (Alexander Mitchell), 1872-1936; Payne, George Henry, 1876-1945; Peabody, Endicott, 1857-1944; Pepper, George Wharton, 1867-1961; Perkins, Frances, 1880-1965; Petersen, William F. (William Ferdinand), 1887-1950; Phelps, William Lyon, 1865-1943; Pinchot, Gifford, 1865-1946; Puckette, Charles McD.; Putnam, George Haven, 1844-1930; Reid, Helen Rogers, 1882-1970; Reid, Ogden Mills, 1882-1947; Reston, James, 1909-1995; Rhine, J. B. (Joseph Banks), 1895-1980; Rice, William Gorham, 1892-; Roberts, Owen J. (Owen Josephus), 1875-1955; Rodgers, Cleveland, 1885-; Rogers, Lindsay, 1891-1970; Roosevelt, Eleanor, 1884-1962; Roosevelt, Franklin D. (Franklin Delano), 1882-1945; Roosevelt, Nicholas, 1893-1982; Roper, Daniel C. (Daniel Calhoun), 1867-1943; Ross, Charles G. (Charles Griffith), 1885-1950; Salter, J. T. (John Thomas), 1898-1973; Schoenbrun, David Franz, 1915-; Schurman, Jacob Gould, 1854-1942; Sevareid, Eric, 1912-1992; Seymour, Charles, 1885-1963; Sherwood, Robert E. (Robert Emmet), 1896-1955; Smith, Alfred Emanuel, 1873-1944; Smith, H. Alexander (Howard Alexander), 1880-1966; Smith, Margaret Chase, 1897-1995; Soper, George A. (George Albert), 1870-1948; Sousa, John Philip, 1854-1932; Stetson, Harlan True, 1885-1964; Stevenson, Burton Egbert, 1872-1962; Stimson, Henry L. (Henry Lewis), 1867-1950; Stoddard, Henry L. (Henry Luther), 1861-1947; Stokes, Anson Phelps, 1874-1958; Stokes, Harold Phelps, 1887-1970; Stone, Harlan Fiske, 1872-1946; Strunsky, Simeon, 1879-1948; Sullivan, Mark, 1874-1952; Sulzberger, Arthur Hays, 1891-1968; Sweetser, Arthur, 1888-1968; Swope, Herbert Bayard, 1882-1958; Taft, Charles P. (Charles Phelps), 1897-1983; Taft, Henry W. (Henry Waters), 1859-1945; Taft, Robert A. (Robert Alphonso), 1889-1953; Thacher, Thomas D. (Thomas Day), 1881-1950; Thomas, Norman, 1884-1968; Trudeau, Edward Livingston, 1848-1915; Truman, Harry S., 1884-1972; Underwood, Oscar W. (Oscar Wilder), 1862-1929; Untermyer, Samuel, 1858-1940; Van Name, George Rivet, 1877-; Villard, Oswald Garrison, 1872-1949; Wagner, Robert F. (Robert Ferdinand), 1877-1953; Walsh, Thomas James, 1859-1933; Waring, Thomas Richard, 1871-1935; White, E. B. (Elwyn Brooks), 1899-1985; White, William Allen, 1868-1944; Wickersham, George W. (George Woodward), 1858-1936; Wiggins, James Russell, 1903-2000; Wile, Frederic William, 1873-1941; Willkie, Wendell L. (Wendell Lewis), 1892-1944; Wilson, Edwin Bidwell, 1879-1964; Wise, Stephen S. (Stephen Samuel), 1874-1949; Woods, Arthur, 1870-1942; Woodward, Thomas Mullen, 1884-; Wriston, Henry M. (Henry Merritt), 1889-1978; Young, Owen D., 1874-1962; Yale College (1887- ). Class of 1909; Yale University -- Students
- CORRESPONDENCE, 1908-1969; Series I; 2 linear feet (4 boxes)
  Scope and Contents
  The correspondence is arranged alphabetically by author. Letters written by Stokes are interfiled under the name of the addressee.
  - A, 1929-1930, 1934, 1949, 1953-1954, 1956, 1959-1960, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Acheson, Dean Gooderham (6), 1930, 1945, 1949, 1953, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Andrews, Bert (1), 1951 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Andrews, Paul Shipman (5), 1934, 1948, 1959, 1967, n. d. (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Atkinson, Brooks (1), 1947 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Auchincloss, James Coats (5), 1947-1949, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - B, 1924, 1956-1957 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Bacon, Leonard (2), 1940, 1949 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Baker, Newton Diehl (1), 1936 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Baker, Ray Stannard (4), 1921-1922, 1943 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Baker, Russell (2), 1963 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Barnes, William (1), 1914 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Bassett, Edward Murray (9), 1927-1928, 1930, 1932, 1935-1936 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Bates, Sanford (1), 1932 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Beaverbrook, Lord (2), 1957 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Berry, Charles W. (2), 1930, 1933 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Biddle, Francis (3), 1942, 1957, n. d. (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Boeckle, Florence B. (1), 1941 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Bundy, Harvey Hollister (4), 1924, 1958-1959, n. d. (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Burch, Robert B. (4), 1954, 1957, 1959, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Butler, Nicholas Murray (1), 1933 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - C, 1924, 1927-1928, 1930, 1933, 1937, 1939, 1942-1943, 1949, 1953, 1955-1959 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Canavan, Joseph J. (2), 1938 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Capper, Arthur (3), 1922-1923, 1941 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Carlisle, Floyd Leslie (2), 1930, 1932 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Cass, E. R. (7), 1934-1936, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Catledge, Turner (3), 1959-1967 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Childs, Richard Spencer (2), 1935, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Civil Service Reform Association (7), 1915, 1926, 1940, 1943-1944 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Clark, John Cheesman (2), 1932 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Cleveland, Rex (1), 1910 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Cohen, Julius Henry (1), 1931 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Crocker, S. M. (2), 1926 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Cross, Wilbur Lucius (1), 1930 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - D, 1930, 1957-1958 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Danaher, John Anthony (3), 1940, 1943 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Darling, Jay Norwood (2), 1921 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Davis, Elmer (3), 1939-1940, 1956 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Davis, John William (1), 1931 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Davis, Malcolm Waters (5), 1926 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Davis, Norman H. (7), 1922-1924, 1934 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Dawes, Charles Gates (2), 1922 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Day, Clive (2), 1929 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Day, George Parmly (2), 1921, 1928 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Delaney, John H. (4), 1933 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Derounian, Steven Boghos, (1), 1959 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Deutsch, Maurice, (1), 1935 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Dill, Richard W. (4), 1954, 1956 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Dirksen, Everett McKinley (1), 1966 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Dodd, Frank Courtenay, (3), 1940 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Dodge, Cleveland E. (1), 1956 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Dodge, Marcellus Hartley (2), 1943-1960 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Douglas, Lewis Williams (3), 1928, 1941, 1947 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Duffus, Robert Luthur (6), 1938-1939, 1953, 1956, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Dun, Angus (1), 1954 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - E, 1951, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Eisenhower, Dwight David (2), 1957 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - F, 1931, 1944, 1953, 1956 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Ferreyros, Alfredo (1), 1948 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Finley, John Huston (5), 1914, 1937-1939 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Franklin, Fabian (1), 1935 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Franklin, Freeda (1), 1957 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - G, 1932, 1943, 1949-1950, 1955-1956, undated (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Gault, Robert Harvey (3), 1940, 1944 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Gavit, John Palmer (14), 1914, 1915-1917, 1934-1935, 1941 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Gay, Edwin F. (12), 1920-1923 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Gilbert, Seymour Parker (4), 1921, 1923, 1929 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Grenfell, Sir Wilfred Thomason (1), 1935 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Gruening, Ernest (3), 1953 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - H, 1922, 1924, 1932, 1936, 1952, 1956-1958, 1965, 1967, n. d. (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Hadley, Arthur Twining (3), 1914-1915 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Hard, William (1), 1924 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Hawkins, Elizabeth (2), 1954, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Hays, Will H. (2), 1921, 1924 (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Hayward, Walter Brownell (3), 1921 (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Hazlitt, Henry (5), 1943, 1945, 1947, 1950, 1957 (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Herter, Christian Archibald (2), 1956 (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Hoover, Herbert C. (13), 1926, 1928, 1930, 1940, 1949, 1952, 1957 (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Howells, John Mead (2), 1916 (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - Hughes, Charles Evans (3), 1924-1925 (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - Hylan, John F. (1), 1931 (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - I, J, 1928, 1934-1935, 1956-1957 (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - James, Walter Belknap (3), 1914-1915, 1927 (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - K, 1941, 1946, 1956 (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - Kaempfert, Waldemar (5), 1941, 1944, 1949, 1951 (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - Katzenbach, Nicholas de Belleville (1), 1952, 1956 (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - Kelley, Nicholas (2), 1924 (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - Kent, Frank Richardson (6), 1924, 1928, 1931, 1957 (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - King, Henry Churchill (1), 1925 (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - Klots, Allen Trafford (10), 1931, 1945-1946, 1949, 1953-1954, 1956, 1960, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - Krock, Arthur (18), 1933, 1937-1939, 1944, 1951-1952, 1956-1958 (Box 2, Folder 48)
  - L, 1916, 1931, 1956-1957 (Box 2, Folder 49)
  - Lamont, Thomas William (8), 1919, 1921, 1923, 1929, 1931-1933 (Box 2, Folder 50)
  - Latourette, Kenneth Scott (2), 1950 (Box 2, Folder 50)
  - Laurence, William Leonard (2), 1959 (Box 2, Folder 51)
  - Lawrence, David (5), 1926, 1931, 1943 (Box 2, Folder 51)
  - Leffingwell, Russell Cornell (1), 1923 (Box 2, Folder 52)
  - Lehman, Herbert H. (8), 1934, 1937-1939, 1958 (Box 2, Folder 52)
  - Lippitt, Henry, (4), 1951, 1954-1955, 1957 (Box 2, Folder 53)
  - Lippmann, Walter (3), 1928, 1956 (Box 2, Folder 53)
  - Lohmann, Carl Albert (7), 1929-1930 (Box 2, Folder 54)
  - Loomis, Alfred Lee (1), 1929 (Box 2, Folder 54)
  - Lowry, Edward George (2), 1911-1912 (Box 2, Folder 54)
  - M, 1928, 1933-1935, 1943, 1948, 1954, 1956-1957, 1959 (Box 2, Folder 55)
  - Mac Alarney, Robert Emmet (1), 1910 (Box 2, Folder 56)
  - McAneny, George (6), 1913, 1933-1935 (Box 2, Folder 57)
  - McClintock, Miller (4), 1928-1929 (Box 2, Folder 57)
  - McFarland, John Horace (2), 1929 (Box 2, Folder 58)
  - McGoldrick, Joseph Daniel (4), 1934, n. d. (Box 2, Folder 58)
  - McKee, Joseph V. (1), 1931 (Box 2, Folder 59)
  - McMahon, Brien (2), 1946 (Box 2, Folder 59)
  - McNinch, Frank Ramsay (3), 1935 (Box 2, Folder 59)
  - Mac Veagh, Lincoln (2), 1933, 1952 (Box 2, Folder 59)
  - Maltbie, Milo Roy (5), 1932, 1934-1936 (Box 2, Folder 60)
  - Markel, Lester (5), 1939, 1949, 1956-1957 (Box 2, Folder 60)
  - Mathews, William Rankin (4), 1955-1956, 1959 (Box 2, Folder 60)
  - Mellon, Andrew William (2), 1923 (Box 2, Folder 61)
  - Merz, Charles (16), 1938, 1940, 1944-1945, 1947, 1949, 1951-1952, 1956, 1958 (Box 2, Folder 62)
  - Meyer, Eugene (2), 1933 (Box 2, Folder 63)
  - Mills, Ogden Livingstone (1), 1922 (Box 2, Folder 63)
  - Moran, Frederick A. (10), 1934, 1938, 1947 (Box 2, Folder 64)
  - Moses, Robert (27), 1921-1922, 1926, 1931, 1934-1935, 1938-1940, 1945-1946, 1948-1949 (Box 3, Folder 65)
  - Moses, Robert (44), 1951, 1953-1964, 1966, 1968 (Box 3, Folder 66)
  - Myers, Gustavus (1), 1933 (Box 3, Folder 67)
  - N, 1913, 1921, 1923, 1924, 1926, 1929-1930, 1957, 1959 (Box 3, Folder 68)
  - National Civil Service Reform League (24), 1919, 1922-1923, 1925-1926, 1957, 1959, 1969 (Box 3, Folder 69)
  - National Probation and Parole Association (3), 1959-1960 (Box 3, Folder 70)
  - Nevins, Allan (2), 1951, 1956 (Box 3, Folder 70)
  - Nicholson, Seth Barnes (3), 1941, 1943 (Box 3, Folder 70)
  - O, 1955, 1958, 1963 (Box 3, Folder 71)
  - Ochs, Adolph S. (6), 1928, 1930, 1933, n. d. (Box 3, Folder 72)
  - Ogden, Rollo (6), 1915, 1930-1932, 1935, n. d. (Box 3, Folder 72)
  - Olmsted, Frederick Law (1), 1931 (Box 3, Folder 73)
  - Ordway, Samuel Hanson (1), 1937 (Box 3, Folder 73)
  - Osborn, Henry Fairfield (1), 1931 (Box 3, Folder 73)
  - Osborn, William Church (6), 1922-1924, 1945-1946 (Box 3, Folder 74)
  - Osborne, Lithgow (1), 1955 (Box 3, Folder 74)
  - Osborne, Thomas Mott (1), 1916 (Box 3, Folder 74)
  - Osgood, Cornelius (1), 1938 (Box 3, Folder 75)
  - Oswald, Russell G. (1), 1965 (Box 3, Folder 75)
  - Owens, John Whitefield (1), 1928 (Box 3, Folder 75)
  - P, 1922, 1928, 1930, 1934-1935, 1949, 1952, 1956-1957, 1960-1961 (Box 3, Folder 76)
  - Page, Arthur Wilson (4), 1928-1929 (Box 3, Folder 77)
  - Palmer, Alexander Mitchell (1), 1920 (Box 3, Folder 77)
  - Payne, Geroge Henry (1), 1912 (Box 3, Folder 77)
  - Peabody, Endicott (5), 1932, 1935-1936, 1940 (Box 3, Folder 78)
  - Pepper, George Wharton (1), 1931 (Box 3, Folder 78)
  - Perkins, Frances (18), 1929, 1931-1933, 1959-1961 (Box 3, Folder 79)
  - Petersen, William Ferdinand (6), 1943-1944 (Box 3, Folder 80)
  - Phelps, William Lyon (2), 1939, 1941 (Box 3, Folder 80)
  - Pinchot, Gifford (2), 1922, 1940 (Box 3, Folder 80)
  - Puckette, Charles McD. (40), 1919-1923, 1952, n. d. (Box 3, Folder 81)
  - Putnam, George Haven (2), 1927 (Box 3, Folder 82)
  - R, 1924, 1929-1930, 1936, 1953, 1956-1957, 1960, 1965, n. d. (Box 3, Folder 83)
  - Reid, Helen Rogers (2), 1957 (Box 3, Folder 84)
  - Reid, Ogden Mills (2), 1914, undated (Box 3, Folder 84)
  - Reston, James Barrett (6), 1950, 1952, 1961-1962 (Box 3, Folder 85)
  - Rhine, Joseph Banks (2), 1962 (Box 3, Folder 85)
  - Rice, William Gorham, Jr.(6), 1922-1923, 1932-1933 (Box 3, Folder 86)
  - Roberts, Owen Josephus (1), 1954 (Box 3, Folder 86)
  - Rodgers, Cleveland (1), 1953 (Box 3, Folder 87)
  - Rogers, Lindsay (1), 1949 (Box 3, Folder 87)
  - Roosevelt, Anna Eleanor (1), 1928 (Box 3, Folder 88)
  - Roosevelt, Franklin Delano (3), 1932 (Box 3, Folder 88)
  - Roosevelt, Nicholas (4), 1932, 1953, 1957, undated (Box 3, Folder 89)
  - Roper, Daniel Calhoun (2), 1933 (Box 3, Folder 89)
  - Ross, Charles Griffith (1), 1945 (Box 3, Folder 90)
  - Russell Trust Association (Skull and Bones) (6), 1960-1962 (Box 3, Folder 90)
  - S, 1923-1924, 1926, 1929-1930, 1932-1933, 1936, 1938, 1941, 1947, 1952, 1956-1957, 1960-1962, 1965, 1967 (Box 3, Folder 91)
  - Saburi, Sadao (2), 1922-1923 (Box 3, Folder 92)
  - Salter, John Thomas (3), 1935, 1939 (Box 3, Folder 92)
  - Schoenbrun, David, (1), 1962 (Box 3, Folder 92)